Curriculum Vitae

Personal Information

Name: Gábor Forgács

Telephone: +36-70-949-949-8 Email: <u>forgacsg@gmail.com</u>

notation for forgacsg.github.io



Summary

I am a problem solver with excellent speaking and writing skills. I am able to work on my own initiative as well as part of a team to achieve the best results possible. Through my teaching experience I had the opportunity to engage with several IT teams in organizations of different sizes as well as explore a wide variety of topics in the life of business. During my academic career I felt the desire to pick up technical skills to support my research (mining natural language text for argumentative structures), which led to an increasing interest in the field of data science. I also have had an interest in web development for quite some time and I completed an online bootcamp during the summer of 2020.

Relevant Skills

- Python: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
 Scikit-Learn, Flask, Plotly, Dash
- R: dplyr, ggplot2, tidyverse, R Shiny
- Javascript: MERN stack, D3.js
- SQL: T-SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, BQ
- NoSQL: MongoDB
- Docker

- Gi
- Dashboarding tools: Power BI | Tableaum | Qlik
- GIS: Leaflet, QGIS, Spatial Databases (PostGIS)
- Advanced MS Excel
- MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Visio)

Work Experience

2022 – Data Scientist

British Telecom ROC.

2019 –2022 Senior Data Analyst

British Telecom ROC.

- Analysis of ticket data from various service desk systems
- Data modelling and predictions with Python using ScikitLearn & other packages
- Building API's with Flask
- Dashboard development in Qlik and Python (Dash)
- Deployment with Docker and GitLab CI

2017 – 2019: IT Business Analyst (Business Intelligence)

Cushman & Wakefield

- ETL of client data in Python and SQL Server
- Developing dashboards and reports in PowerBI and Tableau

Historical Payment Reconciliation for key clients based on generated cash-flow

2016 – 2017: **System Analyst**

Cushman & Wakefield

- Ensuring data quality for benchmarking
- Reporting user activity trends, benchmarking data pool contents on a quarterly basis
- Project coordination with external developers

2012 – 2016: English Language Teacher

Tudomány Language School

References: Ericsson, Ixenit, Bayer, British American Tobacco, Deloitte

2014 – 2015: Junior Research Fellow

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Department of History and

Philosophy of Science

2009 – 2011: English Language Teacher

Institution for the Education of Insurance Studies

Education

2017 – 2018: Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science

2011 – 2014: Graduate student at the Budapest University of Technology and Economics,

Department of History and Philosophy of Science

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (University of Pécs)

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching Philosophy (University of Pécs)

Online Course Certificates

Udemy: The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Coursera: Foundations of Business Strategy

Coursera: Competitive Strategy

EdX: Networks, Crowds and Markets

Coursera: Logic: Language and Information 2

Awards, Honours and Memberships

2009: Second Place at the XXIX. Biannual National Scholarly Competition for Students – in

the category of English Theoretical and Descriptive Linguistics

2008: CEEPUS research scholarship at the Karl Franzens Universität, Graz

2005 – 2009: member of the University of Pécs Kerényi Károly Extracurricular Study Fraternity,

Senior in 2007-2008

Language Proficiency

English
 C2 - Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (2009)

• German B2 TELC intermediate exam, type "C"